Nati Gebregorgis

nati.g5684@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio | +966 559264431

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with experience in using Ruby on Rails on the back-end & React on the front-end. For the past two years, I've developed complex projects using React, JavaScript, & Ruby on Rails. Skilled with debugging & collaborating remotely. Seeking opportunities to utilize my skills & grow as a developer.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap.

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Mobile/Responsive Development, Chrome Dev Tools.

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring.

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full Stack Web Developer

Jan 2022 - Present

Mastered intermediate & advanced topics in full-stack development (including Front-End Development, Rails, Git, & DS&A challenges) while building 15+ full-stack projects both independently & via pair-programming. Some of them are listed below:

- Space Travels This is a web application for a company that provides commercial & scientific space travel services. The application will allow users to book rockets & join selected space missions. All information is actual live data from the SpaceX API. Built with: JavaScript, HTML, React, Redux, & API.
- MovieSpace This web application is based on an external API. We selected an API that provides
 data about top-rated movies & then built a web app around it. The web app has two user interfaces.
 Built with: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Webpack & API.
- <u>Budget App</u> This is a web application where you can manage your budget: you have a list of transactions associated with a category so that you can see how much money you spend & on what.
 <u>Built with: PostgreSQL, Ruby On Rails, & BootStrap.</u>
- <u>Riyadh Season</u> This website gives users a little insight or an idea of how Saudi Arabia celebrates the
 Riyadh season annual festival, this year along with the previous one. In addition to, getting to know the
 people behind it. **Built with: JavaScript, HTML, CSS & BootStrap.**
- <u>Math Magicians</u> Math magicians is a website for all the math lovers out there. It's a Single Page App that allows users to make simple calculations & read math-related code. **Built with: React, React testing library, CSS & Routing.**

MICROVERSE

Remote Feb 2022 – Present

Mentor (Volunteer)

- Mentored 10 junior web developers, providing detailed technical support through over 50 code reviews every
- Implemented strategies to help maintain motivation & promote longevity in the program, resulting in a 5% increase in program retention.
- Expanded my network & formed strong bonds with 6 out of 10 mentees.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE Jan 2022 - Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, & full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, & Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, & daily standups to communicate & collaborate with international remote developers.